SIMON ATTFIELD

DETAILS

PHONE

(415)604-6360

EMAII

simattfield@gmail.com

LINKS

Website

Linkedin

Github

SKILLS

HTML/CSS

JavaScript/Typescript

Web components / Custom elements

Accessibility

PROFILE

With around **6 years experience** working for R/GA @ **Google** on several of their **largest marketing sites**, I've developed a passion for clean, readable, and maintainable code with a focus on accessibility and sensible user interactions. With a keen eye for detail and excellent communication skills, I pride myself on easily developing strong working relationships with clients and colleagues alike, with a confident, outgoing, enthusiastic and approachable attitude.

My most recent project has been to create a modular Custom Element based UI framework that can be both dynamic and server side rendered. It incorporates elements from Google's in-house JS framework and can be used across multiple repositories to build anything from full sites, to simple landing pages, or just individual modules, from a JSON file returned from an internal CMS.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior Software Engineer, R/GA @ Google

San Francisco

Oct 2021 — Present

- Build, maintain and take ownership of many of Google's sites. Including Google for Small Business, Google Ads, Google My Business, Google Assistant, Duo, Allo, and Google's Privacy Policy sites.
- Be a point of contact for more junior colleges, as well as clients, on all aspects
 of the build process, as well as progress updates, code quality, and feasibility
 of features within a given timeframe.
- Assess the impact of new features and provide guidance on complexity and time to complete.
- Quickly familiarized with Google's proprietary tooling, as well as standard versions of (but not limited to) Django/Jinja, AngularJS, Python, GCP and App Engine, and Closure Compiler.
- Gained 'HTML/CSS Readability', Google's rating of ability, within the first 6
 months and therefore regularly conduct code reviews for the team, internal
 Googlers, and other agencies in US, India, Japan, and Europe.
- Work on adhoc bug fixes as required, and constantly assess sites for performance and visual bugs and provide, or delegate, fixes swiftly.

Software Engineer, R/GA @ Google

San Francisco

Sep 2016 — Oct 2021

EDUCATION

Intensive bootcamp in JavaScript web applications, Thinkful

Online

May 2016 — Sep 2016

By pair programming, 7 hours a day Monday through Friday, the course focused on using JavaScript in full stack app development, primarily by building a new project every day but also building capstone projects over a week or more. Teaching everything from basic front end to more advanced uses of React & Redux, Express, MongoDB, PostgresQL as well as uses for theoretical concepts/techniques like common algorithms, CRUD and RESTful architecture, MVC and data structures.